AbdulGafar Abodunr<u>in</u>

Software Engineer, Cloud Applications Developer, and Cloud Solutions Architect

Contact

Address

4, Tunde Hassan Street, Ifako Gbagada, Lagos. Nigeria.

Phone

+2348141758964

E-mail

abodunringm@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ in/abodunrin-abdulgafar/

Skills

Python, C#, Java, and JavaScript programming languages

.Net frameworks, Spring boot, and VueJs

Debugging hardware (Infrastructure as code) and software

Docker, Docker Swam, and Kubernetes

DevOps

Data models, data mining, and segmentation techniques

Database systems (SQL and NoSQL).

Basic distributed systems

Knowledge of algorithms and data structures

I am Futurist, Cloud Applications Developer, and Cloud Solutions Architect with hands-on experience in architecting and building applications platforms. I recently completed all Microsoft Azure certification paths. I am an expert in engineering application platform on the cloud.

Work History

2019-10 – Current

Software Engineer and Cloud Applications Developer Sidmach Technologies Nigeria Limited, Lagos, Lagos State.

- Analyze user requirements.
- Write and test code, refining and rewriting it as necessary and communicate with any programmers involved in the project.
- Orchestrate efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Design, build, and monitor DevOps pipelines.
- Design and develop enterprise cloud applications.

2019-02 – 2019-10

Data Engineer and Software Engineer

Sidmach Technologies Nigeria Limited, Lagos, Lagos State.

- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Designed and built data acquisition, migration, and transformation (ELT) strategy.
- Prepared data for prescriptive and predictive modeling.
- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.

2016-10 – 2019-1

Information Management and Data Protection Full-House Solicitors, Lagos, Lagos State

- Conducted research, gathered information from multiple sources and presented the results.
- Promoted the culture of data protection compliance across all units of the organization.
- Designed and implemented data lifecycle.

Education

2018-01 –	Master of Science: Computer Science
2019-10	University of Lagos - University Road Akoka, Yaba, Lagos. Nigeria.
2009-08 – 2015-02	Bachelor of Science: Computer Science Ladoke Akintola University of Technology - PMB4000, Ogbomosho, Oyo-State. Nigeria

Accomplishments

- Developed solid working knowledge of engineering, design and architecture as the Lead Software Developer on a team of five.
- Resolved existing performance issues in the database which optimized the system 50%.
- Collaborated with team of five in the designing and building of DevOps pipelines.

Cloud-Based Software Design

Software research and development

Accounting systems and software

Cloud Native Application Development

Languages

Python C# Java **JavaScript**

- Designed an end-to-end cloud application architecture using Azure Blob Storage, Azure Kubernetes Services, Azure Key Vault, and Azure Sql.
- Became Microsoft Skills-Lab mentor in Data Engineering and Software Development, 16 months after I was a Microsoft Skills-Lab mentee.
- Mentored 25 new interns to bring them up to speed on projects, resulting in quicker overall completion milestones.

Certifications

2020-09	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure Developer Associate</u>
2020-09	Microsoft Certified: <u>DevOps Engineer Expert</u>
2020-08	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure Solutions Architect Expert</u>
2020-08	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure Security Engineer Associate</u>
2020-07	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure Administrator Associate</u>
2020-10	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure Data Engineer Associate</u>
2021-02	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure AI Engineer Associate</u>
2021-02	Microsoft Certified: <u>Data Analyst Associate</u>
2021-01	Microsoft Certified: <u>Azure Data Scientist Associate</u>
2020-10	Technical Sales: The Role of the Sales Engineer (Certificate of Completion, LinkedIn)

Projects

2020-08 -

Present

2020-03

	Technologies used : Azure App Service, Azure Blob, C#, .NET Core, & VueJs.
2020-03 – 2020-08	Sidmach OCR: An enterprise optical character recognition. It is a cloud solution that helps recognize (digitize) receipt, text, and custom forms. It also includes workflow.
	Technologies used: Azure Forms Recognizer, C#, .NET Core & VueJs.
2020-01 – 2020-04	WAEC Results Verification (Beta): An online solution that enables Students, Universities, Polytechnics, Colleges of Education, and other related institutions to check and verify WAEC results at anytime and anywhere in the world. Technologies used: C#, .NET Core, Entity Framework, JavaScript, Azure, Azure App Service.
2019-04 –	Bizkit: An enterprise solution that helps SMEs better manage their

Azure, HTML, & VueJs.

Approval Flow: An enterprise process flow for financial transactions. It is a

workflow solution that ensures orderly, efficient management and financial

businesses. Co-developed the accounting, reporting & security modules. Technologies used: C#, .NET Core, Entity Framework Core, JavaScript,

resources control, and render proper accountability to stakeholders.